Artificial intelligence updates every
Friday at 2:00 p.m. Eastern today,
Friday, April 17th.
And the epigraph for today is this
Anthropic 30 times growth in 15 months
is not a trend, is a phase transition.
You know, in physics, ice melts into
water, water becomes steam. These are
phase transitions.
And that's what's happening is seeing
Anthropic annual recurring revenue or
run rate. It was 1 billion analyzed in
January 25, and it's 30 billion now. So,
it's like 30 times growth.
Anyway,
this is the updated It's actually
updated today. I forgot to change to
April 17th. But you see the new model
Claude Opus 4.7
now takes the lead.
It is leading in all Well, almost all
benchmarks.
Although first testers report, maybe you
shouldn't rush to switch the model and
continue to use 4.6 because 4.7 uses
more tokens, it gets more expensive, and
the benefits are not like obvious at
this point. So, we will see.
Next, Anthropic plugins. Remember in
January when the market crashed for
because of software as a service
companies.
Well, also there was a deep six thing,
but anyway,
they released 11 open-source plugins on
GitHub, which are basically pieces of
text. And it really crushed the market,
right? So, if you go to this GitHub
link, you'll see 11 plugins. So, this is
like productivity, enterprise search,
sales, finance, data, legal, marketing,
and and so on. So, this is example of
legal
plugin. What it is, it's basically bunch
of skills, and each skill it's markdown
file, it's a text file.
So, collection of those text files
crushed the market.
This is another link
also on GitHub. These are financial
services plugins again from Anthropic.
And this is more Claude plugins again
from Anthropic. 33 plugins. And you see
see the list. You can explore them and
learn how to use them.
It's actually very, very easy. So, this
is example how would you install a
plugin.
Once you have it, you do basically
command  plugin install. In this
case, it's mem search.
And this is the GitHub for mem search.
And yeah. So, let's
go
next.
A
few words about MCP context protocol.
Uh
So, this is agent. This is James Bond,
which is running around using pistols
and other tools to do his job, right?
And MCP server is basically a context, a
library, a file cabinet, set of
instructions, files, databases,
whatever. It cannot run around and
shoot. And agent can consult with this
information source.
Uh so, model, it's an agent
C context. So, this is the data context.
And protocol is how they communicate.
Now, it's very easy to create
MCP server. So, this small piece of
Python code is actually is doing this.
So, you from MCP server fast MCP import
fast MCP, you create an object, you
create the tool, the resource, and then
you run it. That's it. That's how simple
it is.
MCP protocol exposes primitive types
like tools, resources, and prompts.
Well, there's more to that, but in its
core, it's very, very simple.
Claude Mythos.
It's a new model which
they kind of announced, but they haven't
released it to the public. They used it
for
cybersecurity projects with some select
partners.
And if you go to this Anthropic page,
there's 245 pages uh report about this
more model, like it's system card, which
is very, very impressive.
So,
uh the word Mythos come from ancient
Greek mythos,
meaning speech, word, utterance, story,
tale, narrative.
So, all
models
from Anthropic
>> [laughter]
>> You see, haiku is a three-line
poetry, right? A sonnet is like 14
lines. Opus, well, it's a huge opus,
piece of literature. And now Mythos,
like mythical something.
So, Anthropic Claude Mythos is
generating concerns because of security,
because it resolved so many security
bugs, and uh
it's very, very powerful model. Anyway,
Claude 4.7 was released yesterday, and
it's very good. So, this Oops, sorry.
This table shows Opus 4.7, 4.6, GPT-4,
Gemini 3.1, and Mythos. And you see, for
example, agentic coding, Opus
4.7 is much better than Opus 4.6, but
it's worse than Mythos preview, and so
on. Mythos is like very, very strong
model, but it wasn't released yet.
And I really like this video by
Matthew Berman. He goes in depth of all
the features and all the benchmarks.
Claude agent SDK.
There is a Python library
called
Claude agent SDK.
And you can download and install it. And
when you call it, when you invoke it,
it actually puts in memory a small
bun executable, a small bun binary. Bun
is
Well, you can think about it as a
compiler for for JavaScript.
And uh
so, your Python script talks to this
module, which is basically Python
wrapper around this CLI agentic loop,
which which is TypeScript JavaScript
thingy, which talks to Claude model in
the cloud. So, you can think about this
CLI as Claude code, Claude code CLI,
which is very good harness to to work
with Claude model. And via this SDK, you
basically have it in memory when you're
running your script. So, very, very
powerful.
Claude agent SDK is available from
different languages. So, Python, of
course, and then TypeScript. Well, the
Claude CLI itself is written in
TypeScript. So, of course, they have
TypeScript. But also it was ported into
Rust, Golang, Kotlin, C++,
and I guess others.
Anthropic advisor strategy. This is the
strategy where you use different models
to do different things. So, when you
need to do something simple, you use
sonnet or haiku, which are smaller
models. But when you need to really
think and plan, then you use Opus. So,
Opus is a consigliere, and then you have
cheaper models to do specific things.
Okay, this is plug for my channel,
channel name Left Selector. Oh, I
haven't updated these numbers, they're
bigger than this. Uh
I always provide slides. You can
download links under the video. And
please, I always ask question under the
video or in comments. Please stop the
video and answer the question. It really
helps me.
Okay, Open Claude.
A lot of updates. Um
and you see, it's well,
April 10th, 12th, 14th, 15th. So, every
day, every second day, they have update.
The recent ones, for example, you see
they added Claude Opus 4.7. And and so
on.
I When I started building digital
employee for myself, I thought I will go
this route, maybe Open Claude, maybe I
will build something similar to Open
Claude. But then I decided to
concentrate on Claude Anthropic Claude,
Claude code, and use this ecosystem, and
it is very rich. It has all the tooling
you need, and it's so much better. So,
okay, but I still, because Open Claude
is so popular,
I still provide information about it.
And these are releases
for Claude code, and you can see again a
lot. So, these are all releases from
April 10th. So, for a week. Again, a lot
of updates.
Now, Anthropic Claude uh
people use Claude code CLI in terminal,
but also there is a Claude desktop.
And recently it was updated to be more
for developer. Like, for example, four
parallel Claude code instances you can
use inside this GUI
in split view layout, integrated browser
preview. When you're working on your
browser application, you can see this
browser right there inside the same
application. Dedicated terminals per
session, code diff viewing, direct pull
request handling with GitHub. Routines
formally scheduled task. This is very
interesting. So, before the scheduling
was inside this application, so you you
to keep the application running for
scheduling to work, but now you can
schedule it on the cloud and run on the
cloud side, if you want to. Routine can
be triggered by a API endpoints, routine
templates,
and so on. Well, it's still new, it's
still lagging, and it still has some
bugs, but well, the future is bright.
Uh,
there are multiple videos showing
different uh skills. So, this video, for
example, top 10 Claude code skills,
plugins, and CLIs.
So, for example, Codex plugin. So, you
can use uh
uh
Codex, which is OpenAI models or some
other models. Well, you don't really
need them for coding, because Claude
does it better, but you can use it, for
example, for adversarial code reviews.
Obsidian skills, uh
Obsidian is for for memory, for data
storage. Uh auto research by Andrej
Karpathy, awesome design MD collection
of design MD files to developing
designs, and so on. Well, okay, so there
are many So, this is 10 skills for web
design.
Oh, this is interesting, skills to
reduce coding mistakes.
It's not a problem nowadays, but it used
to be, like you asking Claude to do
something and it does something else. Or
in addition what you asked, it uh it it
does
>> [snorts]
>> something which you didn't ask it to do,
right? Uh so, uh the wisdom here is to
create rules asking it to do exactly
what you ask, and nothing more. Like,
think before coding, state assumptions,
and surface confusion, write minimum
code that solves the problem, make
surgical edits that touch only what's
necessary, and define verifiable success
criteria. So, you can add those rules
described here uh to your maybe
Claude.md or some other MD files in your
project.
Uh
work with Google Workspace.
So, if you want to send emails, uh like
Google emails, or you want to work with
Google Docs, Google Drive, and so on.
Uh this is a very common uh and there
are libraries which have lots of usage,
lots of downloads, work very well,
coming from Google itself or from third
party.
And this is example from Google itself,
Google Workspace CLI, inclu- oops,
sorry.
Uh includes Claude.md file, Claude
directory, more than 100 agent skills,
built in Rust, so means very fast.
Uh
and yeah, you can use this. For Python,
you can use Composer, which is
commercial solution, or you can use
Google Workspace MCP server, which is
open source MIT. And this is example how
how uh you can use it.
Uh so, it's very very easy to start uh
to make your agent to work with Google
Workspace or process your Gmail email.
Okay, more skills and resources.
I will not go through them, just to show
this ecosystem for Claude code is very
very rich. Whatever you want to do,
there are already solutions which are
already tested and verified and just
ready ready for use.
Uh
InfraNodus, generate ideas.
So,
this is system kind of strange, it shows
you
uh your your project, and you can try to
find
uh like gaps in it, where you can do
something original.
So, you see, map your concepts as a
network, identifies the main topic
clusters, and finds the gap space of
clusters that are weakly connected.
Those gaps are where novel ideas leave.
Okay?
Uh Cogni
uh gives your AI a persistent memory.
So, it has uh three ways to store your
data, so you have relational store,
vector store, and graph store, and they
all work together. So, it's on GitHub,
and you can use it.
Uh next, adding workflow builder to your
agent. So, we currently work on creating
our own agent,
and we want to generate
uh workflows, and we use library
uh
which is a simple JavaScript library,
which we installed and modified using
Claude code.
And uh so, it's basically a canvas in
the browser, and you can put something
and you can connect them, and you can
move them around.
Uh
quite sophisticated. And then you can
save it as a J- JSON file, and then you
can eventually run this JSON as as a
workflow. So, you don't need external
services, you can do everything
using Claude code and something like
that.
Uh
it's called Light graph, and yeah, we
modified it, it's now a little bit
different.
Okay, uh
all other vendors started providing
their own desktop agents. So, it's not
just in the browser. Like, Google Gemini
just released this week desktop
application for macOS and Windows.
And for macOS, built in Swift, requires
uh
recent version of operating system.
Windows app is similar to Microsoft
Copilot. Uh they don't have deep
integration on OS level. Uh Linux
doesn't have it yet. Um so, skills
Okay, notes about Google agent mode.
Gemini Ultra has agent toggle in the
tools. Well, if you're paying 250 a
month, then you get this toggle. Gemini
code assist in VS code and IntelliJ have
agent mode, and Google search now has AI
mode. Okay, Perplexity.
Perplexity Pro, this is what I use,
which is $20 a month. Uh this is just
subscription, it does web research and
answers your questions and advise you.
It's actually very very useful. But they
have the new thing called Perplexity
computer, but it's paid differently. You
have to
pay it for some additional uh credits.
And uh
search subscription, but can perform
multiple step operations. So, it's like
an agent using different models, agents
orchestrating, designed for complex
long-running tasks.
But they have different payment model.
And then they have Perplexity Perplexity
personal computer. They just released it
for Mac, and if you have it installed on
your Mac, you can press command command
like simultaneously, it will pop up. So,
it works locally, it works with your
files. It's like a digital employee
living on your computer. But again, it's
very very early, it's waiting list, it's
buggy, and but again, future is bright.
Uh OpenAI also have desktop application
for both macOS and Windows.
Uh similar like Google.
Uh macOS app supports quick access
shortcut, app integration, VS code,
Notion, voice conversation. Windows app
available Microsoft store, offers
companion window for instant queries,
file uploads, image generation.
Both apps are free to download with some
advanced features reserved for paid
plans. Looking ahead, OpenAI announced
plans for March to build a unified
desktop super app,
uh but we don't see it yet. Uh being
designed around agentic AI and aimed
primarily at developers and enterprise
users. Okay, no Linux app.
Uh next, uh
SeaDance uh 2.0 public. So, it's AI
video generation by ByteDance, coming
from China, proprietary, and apparently
very good.
And then, uh Top View AI agent V2. It
uses SeaDance
2.0 model under under the hood, along
for long storytelling, automatically
breaking prompts and structured
multi-scene storyboards, and so on.
Okay, this is good.
Uh Railway deployment.
When you uh create your application on
something like Lovable or whatever, but
then you want to actually deploy, there
are multiple options, and one of them is
uh Railway,
uh founded 6 years ago, easy to build,
deploy, and scale applications, connect
GitHub repository, and then every time
you submit something to GitHub, it
automatically goes to Railway.
Uh supports instant provisioning
databases like Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB.
Uh pricing usage-based, starting at $5 a
month.
SOC 2 type certified for compliance.
And yeah, you see, it's used by 23% of
Fortune 500 companies.
So, it may be a good way to go.
Railway is a cloud deployment platform,
not a web coding tool.
Right? So, you start with web coding,
but then eventually you move to Railway.
It takes existing code and
handles deploying, scaling, and hosting,
and at the end, it is cheaper than if
you host it on one of those web coding
platforms.
Uh
so, the two categories, web coding and
like deployment, are complementary.
Uh okay, if you want to build an app
fast with no code, use Lovable or Bolt.
If you want to deploy and run reliably,
use Railway.
So, you develop something in Claude
code, you submit it to GitHub, it goes
to Railway Railway, sorry. And then,
what you can do also in Railway, it will
be
some custom URL, but then you can say,
take Cloudflare and
create a domain there, and in DNS
records, point it to this application,
and then you will have a real app with
real domain name.
Okay, uh Moonshots podcast. Well, they
were talking about so many different
features.
One is like SpaceX planning two trillion
IPO mostly by Starlink revenues and so
on. I will not talk about it. Skills to
survive in new world.
Agency, the ability to identify
problems, act independently, and build
solutions without relying on others.
Taste and perspective, your unique life
experience created an unfair advantage.
Judgment and deep generalization,
cross-domain synthesis.
Well, be a human and be different. Okay.
AI is no longer optional. I really like
this video by Julia McCoy
where she explains like you actually
have no choice.
You have to use AI.
Three valuable AI skills, agent
orchestrations,
AI human interface design, and AI safety
and alignment translation. So, if you
become specialist in any of those or
maybe in all three,
then
well, on a job you will be in high
demand.
AI agents on a job market. AI agents
sure thing.
So, a team of autonomous AI agents
working together on cloud, persistent
memory integrations with over a thousand
apps like
Slack, Notion, HubSpot. Company called
Super intend somewhere in San Francisco.
And
only one co-founder which I found.
So, yeah, very interesting idea.
Using multiple agents working together.
Okay, how to set up Hermes agent. Hermes
becoming extremely popular because
you set it up, it's very convenient,
it's better
than open claw. And as it works, it
self-educates, it self-improves, it
becomes better and better. So, this is
Hermes the like
Greek mythology Olympian god of
boundaries, travel, commerce,
communication. So, running very fast,
messenger of gods.
And yeah, this is this is a very good
video
guide how to set it up and how to use.
Comes with 74 pre-installed skills,
supports hundreds of models, and so on.
And
next,
yeah, convert Claude code into Claude
claw.
So, I I told you that I started thinking
about Claude claw
claw, but then not Claude
>> [laughter]
>> about open claw, but then kind of
decided to go with Claude code. But here
he
explains something he calls it Claude
claw. So, it's like open claw, but it's
actually based on code and agent SDK.
And but has all the features which open
claw has.
So, you can do this. It's a smart memory
uses Gemini flash to wash and categorize
conversations into SQLite and Obsidian
separating temporary content from
permanent pin facts.
Okay, so this is probably good way to
go.
Anthropic
growth. Yeah, this is absolutely
amazing. So, this curve this kind of red
curve, this is Anthropic.
And this is how it's revenue grows. So,
this is 2026, 25, 24, 23.
So, it started from almost nothing and
it goes very very fast. And here this
month
it
went ahead of OpenAI. So, Anthropic now
it's at 30 billion
>> [snorts]
>> ARR and OpenAI is only 25. And
consistency, it continues. So, they
decided to concentrate on one thing
which is
building algorithms, reasoning, building
software, like planning.
And because this is something which is
needed everywhere in any business,
not not just software management. And
yeah, they are in very very high demand.
So much so that
they don't have enough chips. So, they
really really they have money, they
don't have chips.
Okay. Uh
Okay, this is layoffs and last month we
had a lot of layoffs from Oracle. But if
you forget about Oracle, then it's
basically about the same this this
month.
Okay.
This is me as usual and thank you.